{
    "id": "73356f60c0994d04b1bc54c6a248ae8b",
    "title": "Sequence Of Tenses",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "They sold the house because it ……………….. old.",
            "description": "A past tense in the principal clause is almost always followed by a past tense in the subordinate clause.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "has been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I found out that he ………………………..",
            "description": "A past tense in the principal clause is almost always followed by a past tense in the subordinate clause.",
            "answers": [
                "is lying",
                "was lying",
                "has lied"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I never thought that I ……………………. see him again.",
            "description": "A past tense in the principal clause is almost always followed by a past tense in the subordinate clause. Would is the past tense form of will. ",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "had"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She replied that she ……………………. better.",
            "description": "A past tense in the principal clause is almost always followed by a past tense in the subordinate clause.",
            "answers": [
                "feel",
                "feels",
                "felt"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Whenever we meet, we ……………………… of our school days.",
            "description": "A present or future tense in the principal clause may be followed by any tense required by the sense.",
            "answers": [
                "talk",
                "talked",
                "would talk"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He was so tired that he ………………………. barely stand.",
            "description": "A past tense in the principal clause is almost always followed by a past tense in the subordinate clause. Could is the past tense form of can. ",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "is able to",
                "could"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He asked again whether supper …………………… ready.",
            "description": "A past tense in the principal clause is almost always followed by a past tense in the subordinate clause.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "will be"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He worked hard that he ……………………….. win the first prize.",
            "description": "Might is the past tense form of may. A past tense in the principal clause is almost always followed by a past tense in the subordinate clause.",
            "answers": [
                "may",
                "can",
                "might"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He said that money ……………………… the root cause of all evil.",
            "description": "A past tense in the principal clause may be followed by a present tense in the subordinate clause when the subordinate clause expresses a universal truth.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "His health has improved since he ……………………… the city.",
            "description": "A present or future tense in the principal clause may be followed by any tense required by the sense.",
            "answers": [
                "leaves",
                "left",
                "had left"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You may come and stay with us whenever you ………………………",
            "description": "A present or future tense in the principal clause may be followed by any tense required by the sense.",
            "answers": [
                "want",
                "wants",
                "wanted"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He rested his horse for it ………………………..",
            "description": "A past tense in the principal clause is almost always followed by a past tense in the subordinate clause.",
            "answers": [
                "limps",
                "was limping",
                "has been limping"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}